Location Brooklyn, New York
Website https://sites.google.com/view/scottspitze
Github https://github.com/spspitze
Email spspitze@gmail.com
Cell (618)698-3012
Citizenship USA, Australia

### Summary

I'm a labor economist interested in improving worker wages, mobility, and productivity. I'm especially interested in worker education (both degree and non-degree) but also worker skills, worker mobility, and firm needs. Experienced in asking and answering research questions, cleaning and analyzing data, leading and mentoring research teams, and communicating with and helping clients. Very experienced with R and the tidyverse, including using these tools to interact with SQL databases. Also have experience with Python and Stata.

## Experience

#### The Burning Glass Institute

Senior Economist Economist June 2023 - Present March 2022 - May 2023

I mainly work on client based projects studying how to improve outcomes for workers, either though education, skills, or occupation selection. Notable projects include

- 1. Using North Carolina administrative data to estimate the ROI for each program in the UNC system.
- 2. Using job profiles and vacancy postings data to study career outcomes for Texas public university and college students and the demand for students by school and major.
- 3. Using job profiles to track worker attainment of non-degree credentials (used NLP techniques to standardize raw credential data). Analyzing how credentials affect worker outcomes to rank credentials and credential providers.

I take client questions and translate them into actionable analysis.

Created an R package to streamline interaction with the company Snowflake server.

## Education

Ph.D. Economics, University of Georgia, 2022

M.A. Economics (Doctoral Track), University of Iowa, 2018.

B.A. Economics, Summa Cum Laude, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 2015.

# Working Papers

"The Equilibrium Effects of Domestic Outsourcing"

"Currency Competition with Uncertain Acceptance: The Case of Cryptocurrencies" with Fan Liang

### Honors & Awards

St. Louis Fed Ph.D. Internship 2021

Bonbright Graduate Assistant 2020-2021

Graduate College Summer Fellowship, University of Iowa 2017

### **Conference Presentations**

 $2022\,$  Society of Labor Economics, Minneapolis

 $2021\,$  St. Louis Fed Ph.D. Interns Workshop

North American Summer Meetings of the Econometric Society, Montréal

2020 90th Annual Meeting of the Southern Economic Association, New Orleans I-85 Macroeconomics Workshop, Atlanta Fed

2019 Mini Conference on Search and Money, Wisconsin School of Business, Madison Midwest Macroeconomics Meetings, University of Georgia, Athens

## **Teaching**

Principles of Macroeconomics, University of Georgia, Fall 2019 Principles of Macroeconomics, University of Iowa, Spring 2018

### Miscellaneous

Programming Languages: Python, R, Stata

## References

#### Gad Levanon

Chief Economist
Burning Glass Institute
Email glevanon@burningglassinstitute.org

#### Roozbeh Hosseini

Professor of Economics University of Georgia Email roozbeh@uga.edu

#### Martin Gervais

Professor of Economics University of Georgia Email martin.gervais@uga.edu